Before we get into the C programming lessons, I think it's a good idea to quickly review the C coding
style that I'll be using throughout the course.
Many companies and individual programmers have a preferred coding style, so the style that I utilize
in this course may or may not align with the style that you're used to, which is the reason for this
brief lesson.
So let's first focus on the head of file coding style Dot H.
And the first information that we'll include in the header, if required or any includes.
And this example I've included ESP if Dot H.
Next will include any macros and defines, and then we can include any external variables and then type
tips regarding type device will provide a description for the type def and add any special notes if
necessary.
Also, we want to postfix E NUM's with an underscore E.
And similarly, for type def structs, we'll postfix them with an underscore T and at the bottom of
the header files will include any public function prototypes.
We'll add a comment for each prototype that includes a description and any notes, if necessary.
Additionally, we'll include a description for each function parameter as well as the return.
If there is a return and it's a non void function.
Next, let's take a look at the coding style for the C source files.
So at the top of the file, we'll provide any necessary includes for the source file.
First of all, include any standard library header files, such as standard bool for Boolean standard
ale for print def and such in string dates, for example.
Next will include any required header files from the ESP IDF.
The examples I've used here are ESP Log Duddridge, which is used for logging messages to the terminal,
ESB error for error handling and envious flash for non-volatile storage.
Then we can include our application files in here as an example.
We have the coding style h header.
Following the includes.
We can lists any global variables and we'll define them with an underscore prefix and use the static
keyword.
If the variable is restricted for use only within the same file, and so if there are global variables
intended to be used outside of this file, then we won't use the static keyword.
Next, in the source files will include any private or static functions, which are functions that are
restricted for use within the file where they are defined.
We'll include a comment for each static function definition and to specify the function aesthetic.
We'll use the static keyword as shown.
Also, I should mention that if you want to call static functions in the file prior to their definition,
then you'll need to include prototypes for them.
However, I will not do this as this is just the style that I'm used to.
It's perfectly fine to include prototypes for static functions, and many programmers actually do prefer
it.
And another aspect of the coding style is that will prefix the file name to the function name.
For example, the coding style static names shown here.
Additionally, within the comments section for the static function definition, we'll provide a description
for the parameters as well as the return if the function is non void.
Lastly, below the static functions will include any public function definitions, and for these, there
is no need for a description as it's already included in the header file.
All right, so that's it for the briefing on the coding style used, and I'll see you in the next lesson.